Deepak Maram

Research

I am broadly interested in computer security, privacy, and applied cryptography. My recent focus has largely been around decentralized systems like blockchains. My research has led to direct industry adoption. CHURP [CCS19] is on Oasis Labs product road map. DECO [CCS20] is licensed from Cornell by Chainlink.

Education

2018-present **Ph.D. in Computer Science**.

Cornell Tech, New York, USA

Advisor: Prof. Ari Juels, GPA: 3.71/4

2012-16 B.Tech in Computer Science with Honors.

Indian Institute of Technology, Bombay, India

GPA: 8.91/10

Publications

[SP21] CanDID: Can-Do Decentralized Identity with Legacy Compatibility, Sybil-Resistance, and Accountability.

D. Maram, H. Malvai, F. Zhang, N. Jean-Louis, A. Frolov, T. Kell, T. Lobban, C. Moy, A. Juels, and A. Miller. In IEEE S&P 2021. To appear.

[CCS20] DECO: Liberating Web Data Using Decentralized Oracles, deco.works. F. Zhang, D. Maram, H. Malvai, S. Goldfeder, and A. Juels. In ACM CCS 2020. To appear.

[CCS19] CHURP: Dynamic-committee Proactive Secret Sharing, churp.io.

D. Maram, F. Zhang, L. Wang, A. Low, Y. Zhang, A. Juels, and D. Song. In Proceedings of the 2019 ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS).

[SIGMOD19] SkinnerDB: Regret-Bounded Query Evaluation via Reinforcement Learning.

> I. Trummer, S. Moseley, D. Maram, S. Jo, and A. Antonakakis. In Proceedings of the 2019 International Conference on Management of Data (SIGMOD).

[SEFM16] Incentive Stackelberg Mean-payoff Games.

A. Gupta, S. Schewe, A. Trivedi, D. Maram, P. Bharath Kumar. In Proceedings of the 2016 Conference on Software Engineering and Formal Methods (SEFM).

Industry Experience

May 2020-present **Cryptography Research Engineer Internship**, *Cloudflare*, Remote.

Design and development of cryptographic alternatives to CAPTCHAs with special emphasis on usability, privacy.

2016-17 **Member of Technical Staff**, *Oracle*, Bangalore.

Summer 2014 **Software Developer Internship**, *Housing.com*, Mumbai.

Honors / Awards

2018 Awarded University Fellowship by Cornell

- 2012 Secured All India Rank 12 in IIT-JEE out of 500,000 students
- 2012 Secured All India Rank 36 in AIEEE out of 1,100,000 students
- 2012 Recipient of KVPY scholarship and attended VIJYOSHI Camp
- 2011 Awarded merit certificate for being in top 1% in National Standard Examination Astronomy

Posters / Talks

2020 CanDID: A Decentralized Identity System.

Presented our work at the Hyperledger Identity WG.

2019 CHURP: Dynamic-committee Proactive Secret Sharing.

Presented our work at the ACM conference on Computer and Communication Security (CCS), London.

Gave a talk at the Initiative for Cryptocurrencies and Contracts (IC3) Winter Retreat, Interlaken.

2018 SkinnerDB: Regret-Bounded Query Evaluation via Reinforcement Learning.

Presented a poster at the Conference on Very Large Data Bases (VLDB) 2018, Rio.

2015 DoS attacks on SCION and SCION Discrete Event Simulator.

Gave a talk at the end of my research internship at ETH Zurich.

2014 Algorithms for solving Parity Games.

Gave a talk at the end of my R&D project at IIT Bombay.

Teaching Experience

- 2016 **Teaching Assistant**, *IIT Bombay*, CS101: Computer Programming.
- 2015 Undergraduate Tutor, IIT Bombay, Data Structures and Algorithms.

Graduate-level Course Work

Advanced Programming Languages, Advanced Operating Systems, Intro to Computer Vision, Security & Privacy Technologies, Cryptocurrency and Smart Contracts, Advances in Intelligent and Learning Agents (UG), Advanced Cryptography (UG), Computational Ring Theory (UG), Graph Theory (UG)

Selected Undergraduate Projects

2016 Intelligent agents for Arcade Learning Environment, IIT Bombay.

Class Project, Guide: Prof. Shivaram Kalyanakrishnan

2015 Discovering network attacks on SCION, ETH Zurich.

Research Internship, Guide: Prof. Adrian Perrig

2015 Experiments with wireless bit-rate adaptation, IIT Bombay.

R&D Project, Guide: Prof. Mythili Vutkuru

2015 Building a compiler from scratch, IIT Bombay.

Class Project, Guide: Prof. Amitabha Sanyal

2014 Designing a 4-Stroke Radial Engine in Box2D, IIT Bombay.

Class Project, Guide: Prof. Parag Chaudhuri

2013 Building Tetris in a functional language, IIT Bombay.

Class Project, Guide: Prof. Amitabha Sanyal

Media Coverage

- Aug 29, 2020 Forbes, "Chainlinks New Acquisition From Cornell University Could Transform Blockchain For Good".
- Aug 29, 2020 *CoinDesk*, "Chainlink Acquires Blockchain Oracle Solution From Cornell University".
- Aug 29, 2020 *CoinTelegraph*, "Chainlink acquires a privacy-preserving oracle protocol from Cornell University".
- Aug 29, 2020 PR Newswire, "Chainlink Acquires DECO from Cornell University".
- Mar 30, 2019 MIT Tech Review China, "The whereabouts of 4 million bitcoins worldwide are missing".

Service / Extra-curriculars

- 2019 Served as the treasurer of PhD student organization At Cornell Tech (PACT)
- 2019 Co-organizer of Computer Science Admitted PhD Student Visit Day
- 2019 Co-organizer of Cornell Tech Security Seminar
- 2016 Worked as a member of *Insight*, the IIT-Bombay newsletter, and contributed several articles for the same
- 2014 Awared first prize at the XLR8 competition for designing a Wireless Controlled Bot
- 2003-07 Won first prize in multiple district-level chess tournaments in Under-8, Under-10 and Under-12 categories